We think there is a new development
paradigm in agentic development. The
primary challenges in agentic
development are it's non-deterministic.
LLMs and agents are constantly a little
bit outdated. Their knowledge is at
least a few months old from the time the
last model was trained. LLMs and agents
have a bias for re-implementation versus
reuse because creating software is
cheaper than ever before. And then I
think of LLMs and agents as cheap then
expensive. They are cheap in the sense
that you can build things so much faster
and with so much less human effort than
before. But then once you start using
them, now [music] Opus 4/6 runs with its
fast mode that is, you know, 2 and 1/2
times the speed at 6 times the cost, you
know, and already at the top model, it's
amazing. It adds up. So, there's a lot
of problems there, guy. What is the
solution to this?
The hammer that we have is context. LLMs
eventually are just stateless machines
that we pass a bunch of context to when
they calculate their weights and they
figure out what the next words are. And
so, managing what are the words that
come in, what is the information that
comes in,
is really our primary tool. An easy way
to understand this is is to think about
humans. What are your tools for managing
a team?
Communication. Well, that that's that's
really, you know, how you can work with
it, you know, how do you
incentivize behavior as in, you know,
what do you respond to and how do you
respond to it? And there are a lot of
types of context. There are rules that
you are kind of kind of explicitly and
aggressively pushing. There are skills
that you are hinting and making
available to the agent to try and pull
down. There are docs, that is
information that is available for the
agents to find and use at its time. And
I'm sure there will be other variations
of how do you drive the agents to
consume and load the right context. And
and then you have to think for yourself
when you think about the development
paradigm, how do you manage that
context? When we use something like
context, what are the what is the key to
to using context and making agentic
development successful? So, I think
there's a bit of a loop here that we can
talk about more, but
the the sequence of steps are
one, you have to define and capture,
kind of write down,
what it is that you want the agent to
do. That's often times quite hard. You
know, I think we've had some analogies
in our in other conversations where, you
know, if someone asks you, "What do you
want for your birthday?" You know, you
it's easy to say, "Well, you know, you
should just know it."
Uh but I've got a list, guy. I never
thought you'd ask for it. We can start I
can start.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh so, a list is useful. It's useful,
you know, something for me to do.
>> But it makes you But the doesn't it?
When when you know, it's hard to just be
able to go uh this is what I want. You
have to actually, you know, spend time
to think about Exactly. What is the
answer? Yeah, and even more so when you
have a team, right, that has opinions
and preferences. Not everybody agrees
things. And so, you have to have some of
those conversations and write that down.
So, you have to define the correct
behavior. And there are many, many
levels of that. There might be the
correct behavior in a specific product
in the specific screen that you're
modifying. Uh there might be you know,
overall company uh practices or in
ecosystems uh best practices. But you
have to define that. You have to capture
that. It's totally okay to use agents,
to use LLMs to help you write this down,
right, and then refine it. But these are
the documents or the definitions that
are important for you to review and to
ensure that they are correct. Call them
specs, call them docs, call them
whatever it is that you want, but you
have to define those. Uh once you've
done those, you need to evaluate how
well do they work. Um I think it's easy
to understand that if you wrote uh you
know, a 20-page document to the LLM, uh
and it was just, you know, repeating and
giving analogies and, you know, all all
some things like that. Uh, it would be
harder for the other one to understand
what you meant than if you gave a very
concise set of bullets. Again, very
similar to humans. Uh, so those are
relatively easy to imagine how one might
be better than the other, but it it
really is a lot more elaborate than
that. Uh, and you need to consider
different models, understand different
formats of communication differently,
uh, different, uh, types of instructions
married, for instance, code examples
versus others that married more kind of
looseness. Uh, there are many, many
different variations. And so for that,
and we've spoken about this at length,
including in our last conversation on
this podcast, uh, you have to build a
competency to evaluate.
I find the best analogy here is to think
about monitoring runtime systems. The
the the closest analogy to have to kind
of non-deterministic systems, uh, is is
servers. Is they run and we understand
that, you know, you have to uh,
instrument the systems, you have to, you
know, observe them. DevOps has taught us
that. And so similarly for agentic
development, you have to, uh, be able to
assess and evaluate how well does
something work so that you you you can
monitor, you can try it, you can see how
often it works. Mhm.
>> [music]